<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>ktouch.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Ktouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KTouch</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKTouchxx</name>
  <summary>Touch Typing Tutor</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Výuka psaní na stroji</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Tutor de mecanografía al tacto</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Konekirjoituksen ohjaaja</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Schriefmaschien öven</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Typcursus</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Nauczyciel bezwzrokowego pisania</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Professor de Dactilografia</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Aulas de digitação</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Výuka písania na stroji</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Maskinskrivningsträning</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Навчання комп’ютерного набору</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxTouch Typing Tutorxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KTouch is a typewriter trainer for learning to touch type. It provides you with text to train on and adjusts to different levels depending on how good you are. It displays your keyboard and indicates which key to press next and which is the correct finger to use. You learn typing with all fingers, step by step, without having to look down at the keyboard to find your keys. It is convenient for all ages and the perfect typing tutor for schools, universities, and personal use. KTouch ships with dozens of different courses in many languages and a comfortable course editor. Different keyboard layouts are supported and new user-defined layouts can be created. During training, KTouch collects comprehensive statistical information to help you or your teacher to analyze your progress.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">KTouch is en Programm, mit dat Du Schriefmaschien schrieven lehren kannst. Dat stellt Di de Öövtexten praat un passt de Sworheit dor na an, wo goot Du al büst. Dat wiest Dien Tastatuur, de Tast, de Du drücken schallst un den richtigen Finger dor för. Du lehrst dat Tippen mit all Fingers Schritt för Schritt, un ok, ahn dat Du na nerrn op de Tasten un Dien Fingers kieken muttst. Dat is goot för jünger un ok för öller Lüüd un en goot Tipplehrer för Scholen un Universiteten. Dor sünd KTouch en Barg verscheden Lexen in vele Spraken bi un en kommood Lexeneditor. dat ünnerstütt verscheden Tastanornen, Du kannst ok Dien egen Anornen opstellen. Bi't Öven sammelt KTouch Statistikinformatschonen, mit de Du oder Dien Lehrer Dien Vörankamen bekieken kannst.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KTouch is een oefenprogramma voor blindtypen. Het geeft u oefenteksten en past het oefenniveau aan aan uw huidige vaardigheid. Het toetsenbord wordt getoond, en de volgende toets die u moet aanslaan, en met welke vinger. U leert met alle vingers te typen, stap voor stap, zonder dat u op het toetsenbord naar de toetsen kijkt. Het is voor alle leeftijden geschikt, en perfect om te leren typen op school, de universiteit, of thuis. KTouch komt met tientallen verschillende cursussen in vele talen, en bevat een handige cursusbewerker. Diverse toetsenbordindelingen worden ondersteund, en u kunt ook nieuwe zelf aanmaken. Tijdens de oefeningen verzamelt KTouch uitvoerige statistische informatie, voor het beoordelen van uw vorderingen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KTouch jest trenerem bezwzrokowego pisania na klawiaturze. Dostarcza teksty do ćwiczeń i dostosowuje się do poziomu użytkownika. Wyświetla klawiaturę, wskazuje, które klawisze nacisnąć i jakim palcem. Dzięki programowi uczysz się pisać wszystkimi palcami. Jest wygodny dla użytkowników w różnym wieku i idealny do ćwiczenia pisania w szkołach, uniwersytetach i czasie prywatnym. KTouch jest dostarczany z wieloma kursami w różnych językach oraz wygodnym edytorem kursów. Obsługiwane są różne układy klawiatury, można także dodawać układy stworzone przez użytkownika. Podczas ćwiczeń, KTouch zbiera wiele informacji statystycznych, aby pomóc tobie lub twojemu nauczycielowi analizować twój postęp.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KTouch é um treinador de dactilografia que o ensina a escrever à máquina. Oferece-lhe algum texto para treinar e ajusta-se a diferentes níveis, dependendo de quão bom você é. Ele mostra o seu teclado e indica a tecla a carregar a seguir e qual o dedo correcto a usar. Você aprende a escrever com todos os dedos, passo-a-passo, sem ter de olhar para baixo para o teclado e descobrir as suas teclas. É conveniente para todas as idades e é o tutor de escrita perfeito para escolas, universidades e uso pessoal. O KTouch vem com dezenas de exercícios diferentes em várias línguas e tem um editor de exercícios confortável. São suportados diferentes formatos de teclado e poderá criar novos formatos definidos pelo utilizador. Durante o exercício, o KTouch recolhe alguma informação estatística completa para o ajudar ou ao seu professor a analisar o seu progresso.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KTouch é um programa que ensina a usar um teclado para digitação. Ele disponibiliza alguns textos para treinar e ajusta-se a diferentes níveis, dependendo da sua habilidade. Ele mostra o seu teclado e indica a próxima tecla a pressionar e qual o dedo correto a ser usado. Você aprende a digitar com todos os dedos, passo a passo, sem precisar olhar para o teclado e encontrar as teclas. É conveniente para todas as idades e é o tutor de digitação perfeito para escolas, universidades e uso pessoal. O KTouch vem com dezenas de exercícios diferentes em vários idiomas e tem um confortável editor de exercícios. São suportados diferentes leiautes de teclado e novos leiautes podem ser criados pelo usuário. Durante o treino, o KTouch recolhe informações estatísticas para ajudar você ou seu professor a analisar o seu progresso.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KTouch je tréner písacieho stroja na výuku písania na stroji. Poskytuje vám texty na tréning a úpravu na rôzne úrovne v závislosti od vašej pokročilosti. Zobrazuje klávesnicu a ukazuje, ktoré klávesy treba najbližšie stlačiť a ktorý je správny prst na použitie. Naučíte sa písať všetkými prstami, krok za krokom bez nutnosti pozerať sa dolu na klávesnicu, aby ste našli klávesy. Je vhodný pre všetky vekové skupiny a výborný program pre školy, univerzity a osobné použitie. KTouch obsahuje mnoho rôznych kurzov v mnohých jazykoch a komfortný editor kurzov. Podporuje rôzne rozloženia klávesnice a umožňuje vytvoriť vlastné rozloženia. Počas tréningu zbiera štatistické informácie, aby vám pomohol analyzovať váš postup.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Ktouch är ett program för att lära sig maskinskrivning. Det tillhandahåller en text att öva på, och justeras till olika nivåer, beroende på hur bra du är. Det visar tangentbordet och vilken tangent som ska tryckas ner härnäst, och det riktiga fingret som ska användas. Man lär sig att skriva med alla fingrar, steg för steg, utan att behöva titta ner på tangentbordet hela tiden för att hitta rätt tangenter. Det är bekvämt för alla åldrar och är perfekt för skrivmaskinsövning på skolor, universitet och vid personlig användning. Ktouch levereras med dussintals kurser på många språk och en bekväm kurseditor. Olika tangentbordslayouter stöds och nya användardefinierade layouter kan skapas. Under övningar samlar Ktouch in omfattande statistisk information för att hjälpa dig eller din lärare att analysera dina framsteg.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KTouch — програма для навчання машинопису. Ви вводитимете навчальний текст, а програма визначатиме рівень складності цього тексту, залежно від ваших навичок. У вікні програми ви зможете бачити клавіатуру, підсвічування для клавіш, які слід натискати, та рекомендації щодо пальця, яким це слід робити. Ви зможете навчитися десятипальцевому набору, крок за кроком, не дивлячись на клавіатуру і не шукаючи на ній потрібних вам клавіш. Програму пристосовано для користувачів будь-якого віку, вона є чудовим засобом навчання для шкіл, університетів та особистих потреб. Разом з KTouch постачаються десятки різних курсів багатьма мовами, а також зручний редактор курсів. Передбачено підтримку різних розкладок клавіатур та можливість визначення власних розкладок. Під час навчання KTouch збирає статистичні дані, які допоможуть вам та вашому наставнику проаналізувати поступ навчання.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKTouch is a typewriter trainer for learning to touch type. It provides you with text to train on and adjusts to different levels depending on how good you are. It displays your keyboard and indicates which key to press next and which is the correct finger to use. You learn typing with all fingers, step by step, without having to look down at the keyboard to find your keys. It is convenient for all ages and the perfect typing tutor for schools, universities, and personal use. KTouch ships with dozens of different courses in many languages and a comfortable course editor. Different keyboard layouts are supported and new user-defined layouts can be created. During training, KTouch collects comprehensive statistical information to help you or your teacher to analyze your progress.xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/ktouch/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=ktouch</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/ktouch/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://edu.kde.org/images/screenshots/ktouch.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>ktouch</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
